Katie Davis Papers 2010.0051
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Katie Davis Papers
undated, 1990-2010
2010.0051
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
22.6 Linear feet
Katie Davis is a Connecticut-based children's author and illustrator. This collection contains original works of art, book dummies, correspondence, and manuscripts that relate to eight of her published works. The collection also includes original art and realia pertaining to a copyrighted character that Davis created called Scared Guy.
Biography
Children's book author and illustrator Katie Davis was born in New York City and educated at the American College of Paris and Boston University. After a career in public relations and advertising that proved unsatisfying, Davis decided to follow her dreams and attempt a career as an artist and designer.
In 1986, Davis started her own company, Dirty Dishes, which sold hand-painted ceramics nationwide. Davis also worked as a designer. One of her designs, a character called Scared Guy, was an international success.
In the 1990s, Davis was inspired by her own family to write and illustrate children's books. Based on a car game she invented to entertain her two young children, Davis came up with the idea for Who Hops?, her first book. Since its publication, Davis has written and illustrated multiple children's books which have been awarded several distinguished prizes. In addition, Davis maintains a website that features podcasts and a blog with helpful tips on writing children's literature and book publishing. She is a frequent guest on the ABC affiliate show, Good Morning Connecticut, where she recommends books for children.
General Note
Published Works:
Who Hops?, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 1998.
I Hate to Go to Bed!, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 1999.
Who Hoots?, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 2000.
Scared Stiff, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 2001.
Party Animals, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 2002.
Mabel the Tooth Fairy and How She Got Her Job, San Diego: Harcourt Brace, 2003.
Kindergarten Rocks!, Orlando: Harcourt Brace, 2003.
The Curse of Addy McMahon, New York: Greenwillow Books, 2008.
Little Chicken's Big Day, New York: McElderry, 2011.
Scope and Content
The Katie Davis papers contains web design materials, correspondence, letters from readers, materials from presentations, manuscripts, galleys, story boards, sketches, book dummies and proofs. These materials relate to a number of Davis' books, including: Who Hops?, Who Hoots?, I Hate to go to Bed!, Party Animals, Kindergarten Rocks!, and Mabel the Tooth Fairy. The collection follows the creation of these books from sketches to galleys to finished books. The collection also includes materials on Scared Guy, a design Davis created.
Custodial History
Donated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center by Katie Davis in 2010.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1997-2010
Series II: Published Works, undated, 1997-2005
Series III: Unpublished Works, undated, 1990-1996
Series IV: Promotional Materials, undated, 1992-2008
Series V: Realia, undated, 1994-1998
Artwork.; Authors, American--Connecticut.; Book dummies.; Books.; Brochures.; Children's literature--Connecticut authors.; Children's literature--Connecticut illustrators.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Drawings.; Galley proofs.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Marketing material.; Newspapers.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Publications.; Sketches.
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1997-2010
  - Correspondence from Susan Schneider, editor, Harcourt Brace (12 items), undated, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Michael Stearns, editor, Harcourt Brace (8 items), 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Steve Geck, editor, Greenwillow Books (2 items), Feb-Aug 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence forwarded from Elizabeth Harding, agent, Curtis Brown, Ltd. (5 items), 2002-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from various publishers (7 items), undated, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letters from school children ages 3-9, undated, 3 Feb 2000, Apr 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters from readers, undated, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Presentation responses and letters of recommendation, undated, 1997-2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Presentation evaluations, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Published Works, undated, 1997-2005
  - Subseries A: Published Books, undated, 1997-2005
    - Curse of Addy McMahon, undated, 1999-2001
      - Research -- photocopy of newspaper clipping, Author's plot notes, Preliminary manuscript -- handwritten, using method writing, undated, 15 June 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Annotated galley proof -- with editor Michael Stearn's notes in margins, using pre-production title Family Curse, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - I Hate To Go To Bed!, undated, 1998-1999
      - Book dummies (2 items) -- early drafts with pen/pencil illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Book dummies (3 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Book dummies (2 items) -- 1 item bound with color illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Book dummies (2 items) -- annotated, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Book dummy (1 item) -- bound with color illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Book dummy (1 item) -- bound with color illustrations, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Preliminary art (5 items), Original art for gameboard, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Page proofs -- annotated by editor Susan Schneider (4 items), Tables for color selection (3 items), Thumbnail sketches, undated, 13 Apr 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Galley proofs (2 items), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Kindergarten Rocks!, undated, 2003-2005
      - Tissue sketches -- with sketch book covers, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Book dummies (2 items), Jan 2003, 5 Feb 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Book dummies (3 items), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Color tests (2 items), Storyboards (2 items), Original art by author's son, Benny Davis -- used on page 7, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Page proofs (5 items), undated, 5 Sept 2004 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Galley proofs (2 items), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mabel the Tooth Fairy and How She Got Her Job, undated, 2003
      - Tissue sketches, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Annotated book dummies (3 items), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Annotated book dummies (4 items), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Annotated book dummies (4 items), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Annotated page layouts, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Preliminary art (6 items), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Editor's page notes -- with author's comments in margins, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Tables for color selection, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Annotated page proofs (no text), undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Galley proofs (2 items), 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Party Animals, undated, 2001
      - Tissue sketches, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Book dummies (unbound), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Color copies of thumbnail sketches, Paper sample, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - First production proof (complete), Cover proof, Color studies (2 items), undated, 17 Nov 2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Finished artwork (6 items) -- annotated, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Finished artwork (14 items), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Finished artwork with black line separation (1 item), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Scared Stiff, undated, 2000-2001
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Book dummies (2 items), undated, 14 Mar 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Annotated book dummies (3 items), undated, 16 Mar 2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Annotated book dummies (2 items), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Annotated manuscipt (14 pages), 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Page layouts, 2 May 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Preliminary and alternate artwork (5 items), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Alternate artwork -- matted and signed (7 items), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Finished artwork (23 items), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Finished artwork (4 items), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - First editorial proof, 18 Nov 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Who Hoots?, undated, 1999-2001
      - Contract and royalty statement, 22 Feb 1999, 23 May 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Tissue sketches -- with sketchbook covers, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Preliminary book dummies -- unbound, with tissue sketches (3 items), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Book dummies (3 items) -- annotated by editor Susan Schneider, undated, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Galley proof -- annotated by editor Susan Schneider, 13 Oct 1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Annotated page layouts, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - First editorial proof, 5 Jan 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Second production proof (incomplete), 19-25 Feb 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Galley proof, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - First editorial proof -- board book edition, 23 Oct 2001 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Who Hops?, undated, 1997-2005
      - Preliminary art (6 items), Sketches -- in ink, Photocopies of alternate art, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Finished art -- with black line separations (36 items), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - First editorial proof (1 complete copy, 1 partial copy), 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - First production proof (incomplete), Dec 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Second production proof (incomplete), Jan 1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Third production proof, 12 Mar 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Galley proof -- board book edition, 24 Oct 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Annotated galley proof -- Spanish language edition, 28 Nov 2005 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Trademarked Characters, undated, 1995
    - Scared Guy, undated, 1995
      - Original art (5 items), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Finished art for calendar -- with black line separations, matted (13 items), undated, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Original art (4 items); color copy of alternate art (1 item), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries C: Website Materials, undated, 2006
    - Website design notes and sketches, undated, 16 Nov 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series III: Unpublished Works, undated, 1990-1996
  - Sounds at the Fair, 1996
    - Original art (4 items), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified original art (19 items), undated, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Color copies of unidentified original art (5 items), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Promotional Materials, undated, 1992-2008
  - Author promotional cards, booklets, stickers and pamphlets, undated, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Author press pieces and interviews (11 items), undated, 1998-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book signing photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Book reviews for various books (photocopies), undated, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Promotional pamphlets and press releases from Harcourt Brace, undated, 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Promotional materials for Scared Guy, undated, 1992, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Promotional materials for Who Hops?, undated, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Promotional materials for I Hate To Go To Bed!, undated, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Promotional materials for Who Hoots?, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Promotional materials for Mabel The Tooth Fairy, Sept 2003, Feb 2004 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Promotional materials for The Curse of Addy McMahon, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series V: Realia, undated, 1994-1998
  - I Hate To Go To Bed!, 1998
    - Framed artwork (1 item), 1998 (Box 8)
  - Scared Guy, undated, 1994-1996
    - Boxes of tissues (2), coffee mug (1), baseball caps (2), canvas sneakers (2), keychains (3), wrist watch in box (1), wrist watches in packages (2), magnet sets (2), magnet (1), bottle cap sets (4), picture frame (1), gift wrap bags (2), undated, 1994-1996 (Box 8)
    - Red sweatshirt (1), white t-shirts (3), red t-shirt (1), pair of boxers (1), undated (Box 12)